#Encodergasm Presents
～
（ジェット）ふっ
（エド）ふあーあ
（エド）うん？
Welcome back.  And how was it?
（エド）おかえり　で どう？
Nothing to do with the syndicate...
Oh, they were just thugs!
Dammit, was just a salaried employee...
...they just wanted money to play with.
They went to the cops penniless!
...that gave into his temptations.
Then, what?
じゃあ 何？
All of you caught the criminals, but no clue about the bounty we're really after?
みんな 犯人は
ちゃんと捕まえたのに―
肝心の賞金首の手がかりは なし？
（３人）ああっ
They still use paper just for all the complaints.
（男１）苦情だけは
今でも紙を使うんだからな
Dammit, they're just harassing us.
嫌がらせだよ 全く
しかも資源の無駄だ
AND, it's a waste of valuable resources!
The e-mail server is going down from the sheer number of complaints.
（男２）Ｅメールのサーバーも
苦情でパンクです
There is a movement out there to sue our company for damages.
当社に対して 損害賠償を
請求しようという動きもありまして
What the hell are the bounty-hunters doing?!
（男１）賞金稼ぎの連中は
何をやっとるんだ？
We already have a huge bounty on him!
これだけの賞金を懸けとるんだぞ
（男２）はあ それが…
Yes, however...
Amigo!
（パンチ）アミーゴ！
All you bounty-hunters in the Sol system, how are y'all doing?
太陽系の賞金稼ぎの諸君
元気かな？
Once again, it's time for BIG SHOT!
（ジュディ）
おなじみ ビッグショットの時間よ
（パンチ）
まずは本日のホットニュース
We'll start with today's hot news!
この間の連続ゲート襲撃事件の
犯人が捕まったんだ
They apprehended the culprit in the series of recent Gate assaults!
Really?  The bounty on him was 12 million Woolongs, right?
本当？ 確か賞金は
1200万ウーロンだったわよね
But the weird thing is that 20 culprits were apprehended!
ところが どっこい
捕まった犯人が なんと20人
えっ どういうこと？
What do you mean?
Apparently, they were all caught in the act, but none were the mastermind.
（パンチ）
どいつもこいつも単なる実行犯で
首謀者じゃないらしいんだよ
Then you don't get the reward unless you find that mastermind?
（ジュディ）
じゃあ その真犯人を捕まえないと
賞金は もらえないってこと？
But of course!
（パンチ）もちろん そういうこと
Oh my...
（ジュディ）あーら
捕まえた人たち お気の毒さま
I feel sorry for all the guys who caught the culprits!
Why the hell do these thugs that normally just...
（ジェット）
普段はコンビニ強盗でも
やってるようなチンピラ連中が―
...rob convenience stores attack at the Gates?
何だって みんなして
ゲートなんか襲ってやがる？
Maybe there are fads in crimes?
（スパイク）犯罪にも
流行とか あるんじゃねーの？
Like "Hyperspace Gates are the in thing among today's fashion-conscious kids!"
（フェイ）
“今 位相差空間ゲートが
おしゃれキッズの間で人気沸騰”
"That girl won't even look your way until..."
“今どき ゲートの一つも
襲撃してなきゃ―”
"...you assault at least one Gate!" or something?
“あの子にモテないぞ”とか？
Hey, guys.
ちょっと 旦那方
Why don't we trade the information that we each have?
この際 お互いの持ってる情報を
交換しない？
賞金は仲良く山分けってことで
And split the bounty three ways...
What do you mean?
なんだあ？ それ
大体 お前が言い始めたんだろ
You're the one that started all this, saying...
...that we should research this case on our own.
“このヤマは それぞれ独自に
捜査しましょう”ってな
You also said that the occasional rivalry between comrades would be good for us.
（ジェット）
“仲間同士での競争ってのも―”
“たまには いい刺激に
なるわ”とかも言ってたな
Come on, did the reward amount make you lose your memory?
ったく　賞金の額に
記憶まで やられたか？
What?  You guys were really keen on the idea, too!
（フェイ）何よ　あんたたちだって
結構 張り切ってたくせに
After all, we all wanted the bounty to ourselves, right?
結局 みんな賞金を
独り占めしたいだけなんでしょ？
（ジェット･スパイク）はあー
In this case, all 20 cases were done the same way.
（ジェット）この事件は
20件とも全く同じ手口だ
All of them infiltrated the tollbooth...
どいつも料金所に潜入
...deftly attached the hacking unit...
手際よく
ハッキングユニットを装着
...and in the exact moment that passing ships...
通過する船が支払いで
料金所へアクセスする瞬間―
...access the tollbooth to pay the toll...
...they steal the entire balance from the credit card.
クレジットカードから
全額を一瞬にして強奪
Furthermore, the unit automatically sent the money data that it just stole.
しかも ユニットが自動的に
強奪したマネーデータを転送
It immediately launders all the funds in a bank on Europa...
即座にエウロパの銀行で
マネーロンダリングして―
...making it impossible to track where it went.
金の行き先を
分からなくするって手はずだ
All the culprits that were caught in the act have nothing in common.
捕まった こいつら実行犯は―
年齢 性別 出身 宗教 前科
何をとっても共通点がない
Age, gender, nationality, religion, criminal record...
And on top of it, nobody has any of the money that they supposedly stole.
おまけに盗んだはずの金を
誰も持ってないときた
Well, that's about all I know.
まあ 俺の情報は そんなところだ
How about you?
お前は？
The guy that I nabbed said that he was just following the...
（フェイ）私の捕まえた男は
この犯行を―
“通信販売で買った
マニュアルどおりに―”
...instructions from a manual that he got through mail-order.
“実行した”って言ってたわ
Perhaps the other culprits are reading the same manual that he was?
ひょっとして 他の犯人も
同じマニュアル見たんじゃないの？
Manual?
（ジェット）マニュアル？
This.
（フェイ）これ
（ジェット）うーん？
"A new criminal support software."
“新発売の犯罪支援ソフト”
“今なら
お試し価格でお買い得です”
"Right now, it's a real bargain.  For the low introductory..."
“わずか３万ウーロンで
あなたも大金持ちに”
"...price of 30000 Woolongs, you too can be rich!"
何だ？ こりゃ
What the hell?
It's not easy to be a thief nowadays.
今どき 強盗すんのも楽じゃないわ
I'm sure there are people who want manuals to help them.
マニュアルぐらい
欲しがるやつもいるんでしょう
And where is this mail-order company?
（ジェット）
その通販会社の場所は？
It's a store that's only on the 'net, so I don't know where it was.
（フェイ）
ネットオンリーの店だから
居所が分かんないの
Besides, the store has already closed.
おまけに その店も既に閉店
（ジェット）うーん…
Spike, how about you?
スパイク お前は？
The hacking unit that was placed on the Gates was something that...
ゲートに仕掛けられた
ハッキングユニットは―
よほどゲートのシステムを
知ってなきゃ作れない代物だ
...couldn't be made unless you knew about the Gate system really well.
犯人は恐らく―
The mastermind's likely someone who has some connection to the Gate Corporation.
ゲート公団と何らかの
つながりを持つ人間だろう
That was my hunch, and I investigated that front.
ま そう思って
探りを入れてみたんだが…
The programmers would be fishy...
（ジェット）
プログラマーあたりが怪しいな
...but the guys from the Gate Corporation suddenly became uncooperative.
（スパイク）ゲート公団の連中
途端に非協力的になりやがった
It was as if they knew something, but didn't want us to find out about it.
まるで知られたくないことがある
とでも言わんばかりだったぜ
ひい！ いいいいい
Are you dead?
死んだ？
で 何だっけ？
Where were we?
（フェイ）えっ？
Well, I guess those are the only clues we have for now.
まあ 結局―
今んとこ 手がかりは
これしかないってことだ
Gimme that.
（エド）それ ちょうだい
（ジェット）んん？
Gimme.
ちょーだーい
（ジェット）んん？ ああ
Yeah.
This is a memory cartridge for playing chess over the 'net.
（エド）
これはチェスのネット対戦用
メモリーカートリッジだよ
This piece has one match in its memory.
この駒は
ファイトをメモリーしてるんだ
で このまんま押すと―
And, when you push it, it connects to the 'net.
ネットにつながる
See?
ほら
And this has something to do with this incident?
で これが この事件と
なんか関係あるわけ？
Nothing at all.
じぇーんじぇん
Maybe all of this is a game...
ひょっとして こいつは
ゲームのつもりかもしれんな
For now, continue playing that game with the opponent.
とりあえず その相手と
ゲームの続きをやってみてくれ
Yup.
（エド）あい
I'll go talk to the Gate Corporation guys once more.
（ジェット）俺はもう一度
ゲート公団に あたってみる
Lesse...
（エド）よーし
Eenie, meenie, miney, moe...
どれに しよおかなー
エヘヘ プレイボール
Play ball!
（男１）また賞金稼ぎだと？
構わん 追い返せ
Another bounty hunter?  I don't care, send him back.
But he's asking about a chess-loving programmer...
（男２）それが―
チェス好きのプログラマーの件だと
言ってきたんですが…
What?!
（男１）なんだと？
Jet!
（ジョナサン）ジェット
What, Jonathan, were you another one that...
どうした？ ジョナサン
お前も骨折り損の
くたびれもうけって口か？
...went through all the trouble to get nothing?
This thing isn't that easy.
そんな甘いもんじゃねーよ
I believe we have given out all the information.
（男１）情報は もう全て
提供したはずだよ
What more are you saying you would like to know?
これ以上
何が知りたいと言うのかね？
Sorry, but there is no smoking allowed in this building.
悪いが庁内は全館禁煙でね
Oops.  I'm so sorry...
おおっと これは失礼
Actually I had something that I wanted you to see.
実は あんたらに
見てもらいたいもんがあってね
What is it?
なんだ？
This is a planned game.
（ジェット）
こいつは仕掛けられたゲームだ
You guys at the Gate Corporation should know what this means.
あんたたちゲート公団には
その意味が分かっているはずだ
I mean, to put a bounty on a mastermind that we aren't even sure exists...
そもそも
いるとも決まっていなかった―
首謀者に はやばやと
賞金を懸けるってことは―
...suggests that it's someone you don't want the police to know about, no?
警察に知られたくないやつが
犯人ってことじゃないのか？
Bounty-hunters should just look for their bounties.
賞金稼ぎは
賞金首を捜してればいい
I don't know who you are, and whether or not you used to work for...
元Ｉ.Ｓ.Ｓ.Ｐだか
なんだか知らんが―
余計な詮索は
せんほうが身のためだ
...the ISSP, but it's better for you to not make any extra inquiries.
He's going home.
お帰りだ
丁重にお見送りしてさしあげろ
Make sure he is kindly escorted out of here.
（ノイズ）
Damn this old piece of shit!
ったく このおんぼろ
I believe our risk is too great.
（男２）やはり
リスクが大きすぎたようです
あのことが世間に知られたら…
If that gets out to the general public...
（男１）リスクは承知の上だ
I am fully aware of our risk.
If we don't catch him, the situation will just get worse.
やつを捕まえんことには
事態は ますます悪くなる
But why is a ghost from 50 years ago coming back now...?
（男２）しかし 50年前の亡霊が
どうして今頃？
To think that he gave everyone a chess piece...
（男１）わざわざ全員に
チェスの駒を持たせるとはな
Chessmaster Hex...
チェスマスター ヘックス
So it IS a game that he set up...
（男２）やはり
やつの仕掛けたゲームですか？
Chessmaster Hex...
チェスマスター ヘックス
（ヘックス）
フッ フフフフフフフフフ
（エドの鼻歌）
（鼻歌）
No good.  This doesn't have anything other than chess data in it.
（スパイク）駄目だ　やっぱり
チェスのデータしか入ってない
I wonder what they were going to do with such a thing...
こんなもん
どうするつもりだったのかしら？
この中身に意味がないのなら―
If there is no meaning to the content, maybe the pieces are the message...
こいつ自体が
何かのメッセージなのか？
おおーっ やるやるう フヘヘッ
Great, great!
うわっと　おおー うーん
Spike, I have a name...  Can you investigate the guy?
スパイク これから言う男のことを
調べてくれ
He might be the mastermind behind this whole thing.
今回のヤマの
首謀者かもしれん男だ
（スパイク）おい エド
Hey, Ed.
Ed's really busy right now.
（エド）エドは今 忙しいの
ホーッホッホ
にー ちょいちょいなー
Here, here!
チェーックメイト！
Checkmate!
...or so you thought!
と見せかけて 王手 飛車取り
I'll fork the king and the rook!
（ヘックス）うおお
ホーホッホッホッホッホ…
Indeed!  This is either an idiot or a genius!
全く こいつは
ばかか天才のどっちかじゃな
I like this chap!
気に入ったわい
Chessmaster Hex.  Estimated to be 98 years old.
（スパイク）
チェスマスター ヘックス
推定 98歳
A programmer that had been dubbed a genius from his teens.
10代から天才の名を―
ほしいままにした
プログラマーで―
コスモネットの
チェス選手権では―
In the Cosmo-net chess tournaments, he dominated the champion's seat for decades.
数十年にわたって
チャンピオンの座を独占
30歳で位相差空間ゲートの
制御プログラム開発に参加し―
He began work on the Hyperspace Gate control program when he was 30...
...and created the central control system that all Gates use to this day.
全てのゲートが現在も使っている
中枢制御システムを完成させた
However, that was his fatal error.
でも そのことが
彼の命取りになった
He started to doubt the safety of the Gates he helped create...
ゲートの安全性に自ら疑問を抱いて
実用化に反対し―
...and was against putting them to practical use.
ゲート公団から追放
As a result, he was banned from the Gate Corporation.
Ever since, his whereabouts have been unknown for 50 years.
以後50年間 消息不明
So he's the mastermind behind our current string of crimes...
そいつが今回の首謀者ってわけか
What do you mean?
（フェイ）どういうこと？
復讐にしたって―
I mean, why is he seeking revenge 50 years after the fact?
なんで50年もたった今頃？
こいつの居場所を突き止めりゃ
はっきりするさ
If we figure out where he is, we'll know for sure.
Hey, Ed.
おい エド
Ed's really busy right now.
（エド）エドは今 忙しいの！
Hey, you, quit playing games so much and help out a little...
（フェイ）ちょっと あんた
そんなゲームばっかりやってないで
（フェイ）ちっとは手伝い…
（エド）があーっ
（スパイク）
エド ヘックスってやつの居場所を
突き止めたいんだが
Ed, we want to figure out where a guy named Hex is...
（エド）ヘックス ヘックス
チェスマスター？
Hex...  Hex...  The Chessmaster?!
That's who I'm playing chess against right now!
それ エドがゲームしてる相手だよ
We're almost at the location we got from the trace we did on Ed's chess opponent.
（ジェット）
そろそろ エドのチェス相手を
逆探知した場所だ
スタンバイ いいな？
You guys standing by?
I really don't like this.
（スパイク）気に入らねえな
I mean, he's basically giving us his exact location...
わざわざ自分の居場所を
教えてるようなもんだぜ
Can we even trust that trace in the first place?
（フェイ）大体 その逆探
当てになるわけ？
You think he'd be in a dump like this?
こんな ごみ捨て場みたいな所に…
No, I think it was... that.
いやあ 確か…
あれだ
I had heard once that there was a place where all the scrapped remains of...
老朽化して捨てられた
ゲートの残骸と―
そこに便乗して不法投棄された
宇宙船やらスクラップやらが―
...obsolete Gates were gathered along with scrap metal and abandoned spaceships...
集まっている場所があって―
そこに住みついてる連中がいるって
聞いたことがある
...and that there were people that started living there.
Why the hell do they want to live here of all places?
（フェイ）なんで わざわざ
こんな所に住むわけ？
That area has no nationality, nor a government.
（ジェット）
そこには国籍もなけりゃ
政府もない
You don't have to pay taxes, and there are no cops.
税金も払わなくていいし
警察もいないってことだ
I see...  It's the perfect place to hide yourself.
（スパイク）なるほど
身を隠すにも絶好な場所ってわけだ
It might be a trap...
（ジェット）わなかもしれん
これもゲームの続きなのかも
This might be the continuation of the game.
Whatever happens, happens.
なるようになるさ
空気は あるみたい
Looks like we have air.
Then there is someone here...
（ジェット）やはり 人がいる
よう ジェット
Yo, Jet.
Jonathan!
（ジェット）ジョナサン
お前 なんで ここに？
How the hell did you get here?
Thanks for leading the way!
（ジョナサン）
道案内してくれて感謝するぜ
お前 ずっと つけてきてたのか？
You... were following us the whole time?
Tough luck for you, but I have important business with that guy.
悪いが そいつには
とっても大事な用があるんだ
（エド）うわあー ああ
くっ うっ うう…
So I'll be going ahead.
お先に
ホーッホッホ
What the?
なんだ？
ホッホ
What?
何？
How the hell?
なんで？
（いびき）
What is this?
何なの？
ホッホッホ
何なんだ？
What is this?
ニヒヒ
（男）はーい
Hi!
Peace to the world...
世界に平和を　預金通帳に愛を
...and love to my bank account!
あんたもやる？
You want one?
おっおおー
Wow!  Amazing!
すごい すごーい！
ホーッホッホ
Chessmaster Hex?
チェスマスター ヘックスだな？
All right, give up!
観念するのよ　いいわね？
You guys...
あんたら―
Can you be a little quieter?
ちっと静かにしてくれんかの
Old man!
（ジョナサン）じじい
うううううう…
Don't joke with me!
ふざけんなー！
Hey, wait a minute.
（スパイク）おい ちょっと待て！
You won't get away with pretending to be senile!
ぼけたふりで ごまかそうったって
そうはいかねえ
Who are YOU?
（フェイ）あんた 誰よ？
If you don't hand over the money you stole...
今すぐ 盗んだ金を出さねえと
脳天に穴が開くぜ！
...you'll get a nice hole in your brain!
ホッホー でかい筒じゃの
That's a big tube you got there.
（アントニオ）
何やっとるんじゃ？ ヘックス
Hey, whatcha doin', Hex?
（ヘックス）
おお おお　聞いとくれ
久々のすごい相手なんじゃ
You gotta hear this.  It's my first formidable opponent in quite a while!
Must be some player if you have trouble winning!
（カルロス）
お前さんを手こずらせるくらいじゃ
よっぽどのやつじゃな
But before that, where's lunch?
（ヘックス）
それより昼飯は まだかの？
What are ya saying?  You just ate lunch a while back!
何 言うとる
さっき食うたじゃろうが
Oh, is that so?
（ヘックス）ほうじゃったかの？
Really, you've lost so much of your mind...
（アントニオ）
まあた すっかり
物覚え悪うなってしもた
Who are these guys?
（アントニオ）
まあた すっかり
物覚え悪うなってしもた
こいつら 誰？
（アントニオ）
まあた すっかり
物覚え悪うなってしもた
...that all you can do is play chess!
Dunno.  But you know, this old fogey...
さあ　それより このじいさん
（アントニオ）
まあた すっかり
物覚え悪うなってしもた
さあ　それより このじいさん
（カルロス）
チェス以外のことは
なんもできやせん
さあ　それより このじいさん
Have ya lost it?
（ジョビン）ぼけとんじゃないか？
Like you can speak...  You...
（アントニオ）
お前が言うな お前が
ああ…
To...  To think my life savings are never coming back...
俺の全財産が戻ってこないなんて
くそっ ちきしょう
Damn...  Goddammit...
Anyone and everyone, you and that guy over there...
どいつも こいつも
あいつも そいつも 世の中―
The world is all a mistake!
間違ってるー！
（３人）うわああああー
んぎゃあああー
はっはー
んごおっ
What are we gonna do?  This old man doesn't seem to...
どうすんの？ このじいさん
50年前どころか 昨日のことも
ろくに覚えてないみたいなんだけど
...remember anything about yesterday, let alone 50 years ago!
That's right.
そのとおり
ヘックスは もういない
Hex is no longer here.
Here we merely have an old man that loves games...
ここには ただゲーム好きの
じいさんがいるだけさ
Back then, Hex was riled up for revenge, and planned this all out.
（ジェット）
当時 復讐に燃えていたヘックスは
この計画を仕組み―
He made it so that this incident would happen 50 years later...
ゲートのプログラムが
自動更新される50年後に―
一瞬の隙を狙って―
...during the one moment that the Gate program gets automatically updated.
この事件が起きるように
仕向けたんだ
Even making those that physically commit the crime...
わざわざチェスの駒を
実行犯に持たせて―
...hold chess pieces to hint that it was his doing.
自分の犯行を におわせながらな
However, to that old-timer, 50 years was too long.
だが あのじいさんにとって
50年は長すぎた
He went senile, and had completely forgotten...
すっかり もうろくしちまって
自分の仕掛けた わなのことも―
...about the traps that he himself had set.
まるで忘れちまったらしい
ま あんたたちにとっても
そのほうが好都合だろう
Well, it works out better for you this way.
ゲートの根本的な欠陥について―
Because now you don't have to worry about...
ばらされる心配も
なくなったんだからな
...the fundamental defect in the Gates leaking out.
Although, the price you paid was that WE learned about that defect.
もっとも 代わりに俺たちが
そのことを知っちまったがね
What do you want?  Money?
何が望みだ？
金か？ それとも―
Or... are you planning to leak this information to the press?
ゲートの欠陥を
マスコミに流すつもりか？
Just leave that old guy alone.
（ジェット）あのじいさんを
そっと しといてやってくれ
That's all I want.
望みは それだけだ
It's a good deal, isn't it?
（ジェット）いい取引だろう？
Ed would get lonely if she lost her chess partner.
チェスの相手がいなくなっちゃ
エドのやつが寂しがるだろうからな
You're playing that thing again?
（フェイ）あんた
また それやってんの？
Not again.  Still.
またじゃなくて まだだよ
Still?
まだって…
あんた それ１週間もずっと？
You've been playing that thing this whole WEEK?!
Yeah.
あっそ
I see.
Well, good luck.
まあ 頑張って
Yo, newcomer.  You seem happy today.
（カルロス）よう 新入り
ご機嫌じゃの
Hi!
（ジョナサン）はあい
He's a really easy-going fellow, isn't he?
（アントニオ）
ほんに のんきなやつじゃな
That he is...
（ジョビン）ほうじゃの
Checkmate.
チェックメイト
（エド）うちゃー ああー
I lost...
負けちったー
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
Love...  It is to believe everything.
（フェイ）
愛 それは全てを信じること
Hey now, are you serious?
（スパイク）おいおい マジか？
Love...  It is the heart that provides for all.
（フェイ）
愛 それは全てを与える心
Come on... was that what the story was about?
（ジェット）
おい そんな話だっけ？
（フェイ）
愛 それは全てを受け入れる心
Love...  It is the heart that accepts everything.
（スパイク）どうも怪しいな
You know, this is getting fishy.
（フェイ）ウィットニー
そんなに私を愛して…
Whitney...  You loved me that much.
You really can't trust the previews on this show.
（ジェット）ビバップの予告は
当てになんねえからな
A romantic love story for all you lovers.
（フェイ）恋人たちに贈る
ロマンティック･ラブストーリー
次回
「マイ･ファニー･ヴァレンタイン」
Next episode: My Funny Valentine.
（スパイク）きっと うそだな
I'm sure it's a lie.
Yeah, a lie.  A lie.
（ジェット）ああ うそだ うそ